Preliminary Guide to the History Department records, 1905-2001 RG0073
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
History Department records
1905-2001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Dept. of History
RG0073
28 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include photographs, theses, articles, student records, grades, handbooks, annual reports, correspondence, notes, and evaluations. The material dates from 1905-2001. Subjects of this material include Students for Democratic Society, student protests, Brookland Neighborhood Project (1966-79) student records, grades from the 1930s to the 1960s, Phi Eta Sigma, Faculty assembly, faculty handbooks, departmental evaluations from 1932 through 1994. There are images from Elmer Louis Kayser's book "Bricks without Straw" and other items from his conference room, articles by faculty, course materials for the years 1991-88, and theses. These theses are second and third copies that were directed by the History department for the years 1937-79. There is an additional series which contains material from Professor Edward Berkowitz.
Restrictions on Access
Series 2 is closed to research for 100 years from date of record creation. Series 4 is closed to research for 50 years from date of creation.
Series 7, Subseries 1, Box 19 is restricted due to private student information. Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records.
Acquisition Information
Acquisitions information is unknown. Acquisition added in April 2018 (ACC2018.12).
Historical or Biographical Note
History has been a part of the University's curriculum since the first years of Columbian College. During the freshman and sophomore years, studies included English, Latin, and Greek; geography; arithmetic and algebra; history and antiquities; exercises in reading, speaking and composition; elements of chronology; rhetoric and logic; logarithms, geometry, trigonometry and mensuration; surveying, navigation, conic sections and Euclid's Elements.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include photographs, theses, articles, student records, grades, handbooks, annual reports, correspondence, notes, and evaluations. The material dates from 1905 to 2001. Additional material added in 2018 from Professor Edward Berkowitz.
Subjects of this material include Students for Democratic Society, student protests, Brookland Neighborhood Project (1966-79) student records, grades from the 1930s to the 1960s, Phi Eta Sigma, Faculty assembly, faculty handbooks, departmental evaluations from 1932 through 1994. There are images from Elmer Louis Kayser's book "Bricks without Straw" and other items from his conference room, articles by faculty, course materials for the years 1991-88, and theses. These theses are second and third copies that were directed by the History department for the years 1937-79.
Formerly RG 9.17
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: two are Departmental files; one is Student records; one is Faculty evaluation and course materials; and one is Departmental files and the Students for a Democratic Society
Dissertations, Academic; Student movements; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.); Student evaluation of teachers; Student records; Brookland (Washington, D.C.); Photographs; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University
- Departmental files, 1967-1979; RG0073 Series 1; 1.5 Linear Feet (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains newspaper articles, notes, photographs and negatives. The material dates from 1966-79. Subjects within this series include Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), new left notes, student protests, Brookland neighborhood project with photographs and negatives.
  Formerly ACC#424
  This series has a container list in electronic form, please ask staff for assistance.
- Student records, 1930-1969; RG0073 Series 2; 3 Linear Feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Student records are closed for 100 years from date of record creation.
  This series contains student records and grades. This material dates from the 1930's through the 1960's.
  Formerly ACC#445
- Departmental files, 1932-1994; RG0073 Series 3; 3 Linear Feet
  This series contains handbooks, annual reports, correspondence, and department evaluation. These documents date from 1932-94. Subjects within this series include Phi Eta Sigma and material related to the Faculty Assembly.
  Formerly ACC#449
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Phi Eta Sigma Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Phi Eta Sigma, 1954-1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Steel Gauntlet, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Phi Eta Sigma Prize, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pi Gamma Mu, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Phi Eta Sigma (Records), 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Pictures, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Faculty Handbook, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Faculty Handbook, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Handbook, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Publications by John Hanessian, Jr. (GW Faculty), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Department: Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Promotion and Tenure, 10/1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Report on Faculty, 11/1992 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Long Range Planning, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Evalation of Department, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Department Report, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Academic Evaluation-Spring, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A Critical Self-Evaluation of GW, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    General note
    2 copies
  - Progress Report (GW), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Recruiting Women and Minority Group faculty, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Regular Faculty Assembly-Faculty Senate, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Publications, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ribuffo, Leo Promotion, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum: M.I. Requirements, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Sprouts", undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Department Business, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fiske Meeting, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - The Washington Past Vol. 1 no. 3-4, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Advisory Committee, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Annual Reports: Senate committees, 1970 ca. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Advisory Committee: Experimental Humanities, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ad hoc Committee on Retirement, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - C.E.O.: correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ad hoc Committee on Women, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Working Papers: C.E.O Meeting, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Pro-Seminar Debates, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Pro-Seminar Revisited, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - B.A. Comprehensive, 02/1970-05/1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Pro-Seminar Syllabifrom, 1970 ca. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - GSAS, 1981-1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Factors Motivating the G.W. Faculty, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - GW Bicentennial, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Committee on Objectives, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Memorandum Re: Obstacles to Research, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Linton: Ou Liberal Arts Education, 1977,1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Dean's Report, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Academic Dishonesty, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Teaching Survey Courses, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Department Evaluation, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - FCC Meetings with CCAS Faculty, 04/28/1987-04/29/1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Program and Fellowship Materials, 1970-1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Faculty evaluation and course materials, 1991-1998; RG0073 Series 4; 9.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains faculty evaluations and course materials for the years 1991-98.
  Formerly ACC#802
  This series is restricted for 50 years from date of record creation.
  - Fall Schedule, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fall Background, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spring Background, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Spring Schedule, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Summer Schedule, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Spring Background, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Spring Schedule, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Summer Schedule, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fall Background, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Spring Background, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Summer Background, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Spring Background, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fall Background, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Spring Background, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Spring Schedule, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Summer Schedule, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Summer Background, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Spring Schedule, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Spring Background, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fall Schedule, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Summer Sessions, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Summer Sessions, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Summer Background, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Fall Schedule, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Fall Background, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Fall Schedule, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Summer Schedule, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fall Schedule, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Spring/Summer Faculty Evaluations, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fall Faculty Evaluations, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Spring Faculty Evaluations, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fall Faculty Evaulations, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Spring Faculty Evaluations, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fall Faculty Evaluations, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Spring Faculty Evaluations, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fall Faculty Evaluations, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 39-11 Permanent Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Honors 71, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Islamic Humanities, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History 38 Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - History 39 - 11 Supplemental Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 39-11 [1/2], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 39-11 [2/2], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - 39 Fall [1/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 39 Fall [2/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 39 Fall, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 39 Fall [1/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 39 Fall [2/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 40-11 Spring, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 40-11 Spring, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - 40 Spring, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 40-11 Spring [1/2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - 40-11 Spring [2/2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 40 Spring, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 40-11 Spring, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 108 Spring, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - 60 Fall [1/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - 60 Fall [2/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 101 Fall [1/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 101 Fall [2/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 109 Permanent Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 109 Fall, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - 109 Fall [1/2], 1994 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - 109 Fall [2/2], 1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - 109 Fall, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - 109 Spring [1/2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - 109 Spring [2/2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 109 Fall, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 109 Fall, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - 107 Fall [1/2], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 107 Fall [2/2], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - 107 Fall [1/2], 1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 107 Fall [2/2], 1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - 107 Spring [1/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - 107 Spring [2/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - 108 Permanent Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - 108 Spring [1/2], 1993 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - 108 Spring [2/2], 1993 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - 108 Fall [1/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - 108 Fall [2/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - 110 Permanent materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - 110 Spring, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - 110 Spring [1/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - 110 Spring [2/2], 1995 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - 110 Spring [1/2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - 110 Spring [2/2], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - 110 Spring [1/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - 110 Spring [2/2], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 209 Spring, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Cassette Tapes, undated (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Master sheets for Roots handouts, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - NEH Roots Project Typed Copy, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Roots lecture notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Roots: Rome, Later Church, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Roots: Helleistic Judaism, Christianity, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Roots: Greece, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Roots: Early Hebrews, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Teaching Evaluations, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lost Source on Enmenes, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Plutarch Enmenes, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letters [1/2], undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Letters [2/2], undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Grade Sheets, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bookstore, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Trips to Jordan, Syria, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Departmental files and the Students for a Democratic Society, 1935-1998; RG0073 Series 5; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains brochures, flyers, hearings, reports, hearings, invitations, memorandums, a syllabus, bibliographies, newsletters, exams, constitution, by-lays, telegrams, a photographs, correspondence, and minutes. They range in date from 1935 to 1998. The materials concern the Students for a Democratic Society's (SDS) protests against university research, the Human Resources Research Office (HumRO), war, George Washington University (GW) policies, the GW Board of Trustees, and strikes; an investigation of the SDS by the House of Representatives Committee on Internal Security; History degree requirements; fellowships; committee of research grant; "The Newsletter of the Documentary History of the First Federal Congress 1789-1791"; the General Electric College Bowl photograph, questions submitted by faculty, and questions used by the bowl; lectures; and the History Department's honors program.
  Formerly vertical files
  - History Department, 03/01/1967-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History Department - Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History Department - GW appearance on General Electric College Bowl, 1969, 04/10/1969-10/13/1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History Department - Graduate Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History Department - Lectures, 02/06/1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History Department - Meeting minutes, correspondence, 1935-1938, 02/01/1935-05/15/1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History Department - Special Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History Department - Student Papers, 1974-12/06/1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History Department - Undergraduate Major, 1969-01/11/1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Student Protests Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), 1965-1970, 10/20/1965-05/19/1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Protests Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) - Investigation of SDS at George Washington University, 1969, 07/22/1969-07/24/1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Protests Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) Position on University Research, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Linda Levy Peck records, 1990-2004; RG0073 Series 6 (Box 1, Box 2)
  The two boxes of committee materials contain university confidential records. No length of restriction has been determined yet for such materials across the university.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains working folders from university committees, and 2 folders of syllabai from courses taught by Linda Levy Peck. Committees covered include the Advisory Council on Research (c. 1998-2000), Academic Excellence Committee (2001-2002), the writing program (1999), an advisory group on early modern European studies, the 1998 strategic planning process, and the University Roundtable (1999-2000).
- Edward Berkowitz papers, 1935-2001; RG0073 Series 7; 9 Linear Feet
  Materials in this series were donated by Professor Edward Berkowitz. Material includes course material, department documents, publications and public policy documents. The documents date from 1935-2001.
  Arrangement
  Materials are arranged into three subseries: Class material, Papers and publications and Policy documents.
  - Class material, 1946-2001; Series 6 Subseries 1; 6 Linear Feet
    Materials in this subseries related to the history department and classes taught by Professor Edward Berkowitz. This includes syllabi, course evaluations, candidate searches and other miscellanous documents. The materials date from 1946-2001.
    Arranged alphabetically. The contents of Box 19 are arranged as they were originally organized.
    - 700 Courses, 1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1970s Project, 1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Allida Black Project, 1999; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Journal of Bioethics, 2001; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - APPAM, 1999; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ad Hoc Committee Graduate History Program, 1984-1985; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The American Family, Undated; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - American Studies, 1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Baltimore Conference, 1995-1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Birmingham, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Laurie Block, 1991-1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Elizabeth Boggs, 1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Book orders, 2000; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Book reviews, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Brauer, Carl M., 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Broadcast Pioneers Library, 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Burkhauser, Richard, 1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bush conference, 1997; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cantelon/NIH, 1946-1974; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Carnegie Corporation, 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Carter, Undated; Series 6 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Carter Library, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Carrow Conference, 1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Ceruzzi, Paul, 1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Chapter Outline: Public Policy Toward Disability, Undated; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Citations: In the Press, 1984; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Citations: P.R. Publisher's Listings, 1988; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cohen Reviews, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Coll, Blanche: Oral Histories, 1985-1988; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Coming of Age, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Records, 1963-1965; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Pre-1982, 1974-1981; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cruikshank, 1947-1956; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Danielson, Eric, 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Denker, Joel, 1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - DeWitt, Larry, 1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Dutch Conference, 1994-1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Elder care, 1965; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Falk, Undated; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Florence, 1997; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Fox, Daniel, 1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Freedom Riders, Undated; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - G.A.O., 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Garland Publishing, 1993; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - German History Institute, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Gillon, Steve, 1997; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Government Agencies, 1998-1999; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Graduate admissions, 1998; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Great Society essay, 2000; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hamed, Raouf Abbas, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Leslie M., 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - The Hastings Center, 1999-2001; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Hawley prize, 1994-1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - H.C.F.A., 1997; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hendricks, Rickey, 1994; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Herber retirement dinner, 1999-2000; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Hickel, Walter, 2000; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - History 72 survey, 1998; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Historiography course, 1991-2011; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - History and Social Policy, 1979; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - H-State, 1996; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Honors program, 1993; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Howard, Christopher, 1996; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Huebner, Todd, 1994; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Illusion of Chaos, 1979; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Institute of Medicine, 1997; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - IOM, 1997; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Jacobsen, Charles, Undated; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Jacoby, Sanford, Undated; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - JFK Library, 1961; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Johnson and Education, 1965-1966; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Journal of American History, Undated; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Journal: Disability Policy, 1993-1994; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Journal of Disability Policy, 1999; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Journal of Geronitology Social Sciences, 1997-1998; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Journal of Gerontology, 1997; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Kansas University Press, 1994-1995; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Keller, Hellen, 1996; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Kennedy Project, 1980-1981; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Kutler, 1994; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Leff, Mark, 1994; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Letters, 1962-1965; Series 6 Subseries 6 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Levine, David, 1995; Series 7 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 1, Folder data_value_missing_933acba6684860114421618e9f9637af)